&gt;&gt; To help us with this lesson,
— 为了更好地学习这节课
we're excited to welcome Drew Gray,
我们很高兴地请到了 Drew Gray
who's leading the self-driving car team at Otto
他是 Otto 公司的无人驾驶团队主管
which is now part of Uber. Thanks for joining us Drew.
Otto 现在已经被优步收购 Drew 谢谢你来到这里
&gt;&gt; You're welcome.
— 不客气
&gt;&gt; So Drew, can you tell us a little bit more about how
— Drew 你能否向我们简要介绍一下
you use deep learning for self-driving cars at Otto.
Otto 公司是如何使用深度学习技术研发无人驾驶车的呢？
&gt;&gt; For sure. Deep neural networks have been a big focus of my work at Otto.
— 没问题 深度神经网络在我们 Otto 公司的工作中拥有核心地位
We're exploring whether we can get a car to drive itself,
我们正在探索 是否能够不使用其他技术
using only deep neural networks and nothing else.
而只利用深度神经网络 来实现汽车的无人驾驶
Sometimes we call that behavioral cloning
有时我们称之为行为克隆
because you're training the network that clone human driving behavior.
我们训练神经网络是为了克隆人类的驾驶行为
Well, sometimes it's called end-to-end learning because the network
有时候我们也称其为端到端学习
is learning to predict the correct steering angle and speed,
因为我们的神经网络需要学会只利用传感器的输入
using only the inputs from the sensors.
来估计正确的方向盘转向角和车速
&gt;&gt; So as I understand it, deep learning isn't
— 按照我的理解
the only approach to building a self-driving car.
深度学习并不是开发无人驾驶车的唯一途径
For a number of years, people have been working on
在过去很多年中 人们一直在使用
a more traditional sort of robotics approach.
更加传统的机器人学方法
So, why go with deep learning over robotics approach?
那么 为什么选择深度学习 而不是机器人学方法呢？
&gt;&gt; Right. Well, my Ph.D. is actually in control theory and artificial intelligence.
— 好 我来解释一下 我在博士阶段研究的是控制理论和人工智能
So, I spent a lot of time working on both approaches.
我花了大量时间研究了深度学习和机器人学这两种途径
In fact, engineers at Otto are working on
实际上 Otto 的无人驾驶工程师们正在同时使用
both deep learning and the standard robotics approach.
深度学习与标准的机器人学这两种方法
I'm working on deep learning because I think it has the potential to
我选择深度学习 是因为我认为该技术
fundamentally change how we develop self-driving cars.
有可能彻底颠覆无人驾驶车开发方式
&gt;&gt; Cool. Can you explain a little bit more about
— 那太棒了 能否稍微详细地解释一下
the difference between the deep learning approach versus the robotics approach.
深度学习和机器人学这两种方法之间的差异？
&gt;&gt; The robotics approach in building self-driving cars involves a lot
— 采用机器人学这一途径开发无人驾驶车
of detail knowledge about sensors, controls and planning.
需要充分掌握传感器 控制和规划的相关知识
With the deep learning approach,
而深度学习这一途径
we don't have to program all that detail knowledge into the vehicle.
则不需要把这些细节内容编入车辆的程序中
We simply feed all the information we have into the network,
我们只需把获得的信息输入网络
and then we let the network figure out on its own what's important.
而后 就让神经网络自行判断出各种信息的重要等级
Also, deep learning allows us to build a feedback loop where the more we drive,
此外 深度学习还可以构建一个反馈环路
the more data we can collect,
车行驶的距离越长 收集到的数据就越多
which in turn allows us to learn how to drive even better.
最终 我们就能知道如何完善自动驾驶技术
&gt;&gt; So, what you're doing sounds pretty similar to what
— 这么说来 你们目前正在做的工作
students will be doing in their final project at the end of this module,
和学员在这个模块结束时要做的项目非常类似
only they'll be implementing behavioral cloning and simulator.
唯一的区别在于 学员们只是在模拟器上实现行为克隆
&gt;&gt; Well, a simulator certainly makes things easier,
— 是的 模拟器能简化很多事情
but the overarching principles are the
不过 无论是在模拟器中 还是在真正的汽车上
same whether you're in the simulator or a real vehicle.
实现无人驾驶的基本原理是相同的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, but can you actually drive a real vehicle with just a deep neural network?
— 是的 但是我们真的可以驾驶只配备深度神经网络的车辆吗？
&gt;&gt; You can. We actually recently drove 20 miles
当然可以 前不久我们在旧金山的机场高速上开了个来回
down the highway in San Francisco to the airport and back,
一共行驶了 20 英里
without touching the steering wheel once.
整个过程一次都没有手动干预方向盘
&gt;&gt; Wow. So it really works.
— 哇 所以这真的可以实现
Well then, let's get started building a deep neural network.
那么接下来 我们开始搭建深度神经网络吧
&gt;&gt; Let's do it.
— 开始动手吧